<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Experience the World of Coffee through GUSTATORY Subscription</title>
    <link href="/Experience-the-World-of-Coffee-through-GUSTATORY-Subscription/"/>
    <url>/Experience-the-World-of-Coffee-through-GUSTATORY-Subscription/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>Subscribe to GUSTATORY, a multi-roaster coffee selectionto discover and enjoy better.</em></strong> <span id="more"></span></p><div class="note note-danger">            <p>Posted as a serial</p><p>Certain contents copyright GUSTATORY</p>          </div><div class="note note-info">            <p>At a glance:</p><ul><li><p>12//24 Roasters: SlowMov, Bell Lane Coffee</p></li><li><p>11//24 Roasters: Kawa, Nano Kaffee, MOK Coffee</p></li></ul>          </div><p><a href="https://www.gustatory.co/"><strong>GUSTATORY</strong></a> isa UK-based speciality coffee subscription service that features all themost exciting of UK, USA and European speciality coffee roasters. BeingEurope's only multi-roaster coffee subscription, GUSTATORY'sever-rotating roaster discoveries serve the very best independent coffeeroasters from around the world in terms of quality, ethics andsustainability, with up to 43% savings (The truth is, the British arereally good at marketing).</p><p>Provided with a variety of subscription choices, I opt for "Plus 87Coffees", serving best-in-class speciality coffees with a minimum87+/100 (SCA) score. Meanwhile, I am trying to give my own notes on eachpod, though I just drink, never taste or judge one. <strong>My</strong>uses a 50 point scale to reflect my own impression on coffee beanitself, consisting of nose (10), flavour (15), body (15) and utility(10), in a nutshell.</p><h3 id="december-2024">December 2024</h3><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post5/241129001.jpg"title="SlowMov, Ethiopia, Laayyoo Natural" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post5/241129002.jpg"title="Bell Lane Coffee, Heiner Lazo, Colombia, Washed" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"></div></div><h4 id="slowmov-ethiopia-laayyoo-natural">SlowMov, Ethiopia, LaayyooNatural</h4><blockquote><p>Profile</p><p>Roaster: SlowMov, Barcelona, Spain</p><p>Region: Guji</p><p>Producer: Raro Nensebo Drying Station</p><p>Variety: 74110 &amp; 74112 Heirloom</p><p>Process: Natural</p></blockquote><p><a href="https://slowmov.com/">SlowMov</a> is a speciality coffeeshop and roastery located in Barcelona’s charming Gracia neighbourhood.SlowMov is a portmanteau of the words Slow and Movement because theywanted to give people the time and space to discover and enjoy finespecialty coffees. I like the word movement because it is something thatmoves forward and changes but with cadence and respect for the timeneeded for each process.</p><p>The word Laayyoo refers to an indigenous tree growing in Guji area,used for shade on coffee plantations. This natural coffee is producedthrough a stringent selection process that eliminates all overripe andunderripe cherries, resulting in a clean cup free of excessivefermentation flavours.</p><p>With typical light roasted, this lot has a rather subtle flavourprofile, remaining somewhat mild even at high extraction levels. Theacidity is quite nuanced, with a faint hint of citrus. Finer grindsettings and higher brewing temperatures may reveal some berry-likenotes. (<strong>My</strong> 40/50)</p><h4 id="bell-lane-coffee-heiner-lazo-colombia-washed">Bell Lane Coffee,Heiner Lazo, Colombia, Washed</h4><blockquote><p>Profile</p><ul><li>Roaster: Bell Lane Coffee, Mullingar, Ireland<br /></li><li>Region: Finca el Rubi, Huila<br /></li><li>Producer: Heiner Lazo<br /></li><li>Variety: Pink Bourbon<br /></li><li>Process: Washed</li></ul></blockquote><p><a href="https://www.belllane.ie/">Bell Lane Coffee</a> was foundedin 2012 in Mullingar, eastern Ireland. Their mission is simple: to bringthe delight of freshly roasted, seasonal coffee straight to your mug.Since 2012, they've embarked on an incredible journey, exploring theworld in search of the finest beans and forging meaningful connectionswith exceptional coffee producers.</p><p>The story of Finca el Rubi starts 25 years ago when it was sold tothe current owner Heiner Lazo and his wife Johanna. Heiner has neverstopped innovating, adapting, and changing the farm's processing methodsto improve results and quality. They plant Papayo, Pink Bourbon and SL28 in 6-hectare farm. Specifically, the coffee in my hand, cultivatedfrom hybrid of Red and Yellow Bourbon, Pink Bourbon is said to have beenfirst found in Huila, and is gaining increasing attention nowadays.</p><p>This Pink Bourbon offers a complex aroma profile, starting withsubtle woody notes followed by the sweetness of fruits, primarily orangeand citrus. On the palate, it delivers the sweetness dominated bycrushed cocoa and raspberry, complemented by hints of caramel in thefinish. Beyond expectation. (<strong>My</strong> 42/50)</p><h3 id="november-2024">November 2024</h3><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post5/241104001.jpg"title="Kawa, Ethiopia, Duwancho, Natural" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post5/241104002.jpg"title="Nano Kaffee, Rwanda, Dukunde, Organic" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post5/241104003.jpg"title="MOK Coffee, Ethiopia, Tibebu Roba, Natural" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"></div></div><h4 id="kawa-ethiopia-duwancho-natural">Kawa, Ethiopia, Duwancho,Natural</h4><blockquote><p>Profile</p><ul><li>Roaster: Kawa Coffee, Paris, France<br /></li><li>Region: Sidamo<br /></li><li>Producer: Famille Dukamo</li><li>Variety: 71458 Heirloom<br /></li><li>Process: Natural</li></ul></blockquote><p><a href="https://shop.kawa.coffee/en/">Kawa coffee</a> is one ofexceptional roasters in Paris, and focus entirely on roasting, with everowning their own cafes subsidiary to this. Providing an extensive rangeof coffee selection and brewing gear, Kawa is devoting towards a genuinecoffee community and valuing the emerging market like China. Despite abit heavy commercial marketing, roasting quality has earned them a placein the highly competitive specialty coffee scene.</p><p>This elegant Ethiopian highland Arabica grows in the Sidamo region,one of the most popular coffee-producing regions. It is a garden coffeefrom many small family farms at an altitude of 1,750 to 2,200 metres.Meanwhile, Duwancho, a native fruit of keramo of Sidamo, inspires thecoffee named after it, celebrated for its fruity notes.</p><p>Honestly, this lot doesn't fully live up to my expectations, despitethe captivating aroma when I first opened the bag. After brewing, thearoma but the acidity upon the palate is bright and lively. Notes ofmango and orange come through in the cup, with a pleasant sweetness. Inthe finish, there's a hint of elusive floral notes. Different brewingmethods don't yield significant variations, but as it cools, the flavourimproves. (<strong>My</strong> 42/50)</p><h4 id="nano-kaffee-rwanda-dukunde-organic">Nano Kaffee, Rwanda,Dukunde, Organic</h4><blockquote><p>Profile</p><ul><li>Roaster: Nano Kaffee, Berlin, Germany<br /></li><li>Region: Province du Nord<br /></li><li>Producer: Dukunde Kawa Musasa Cooperative<br /></li><li>Variety: Red Bourbon<br /></li><li>Process: Natural</li></ul></blockquote><p><a href="https://nano-kaffee.de/en">Nano Kaffee</a> is obsessed withemphasising its role as a responsible business. It is undoubtedly true,yet tends to distract us from focusing on the coffee itself. Typically,when a business reaches the top of its industry, it begins to stresscreating social and ecological added value - something Nano Kaffeeclearly exemplifies.</p><p>In Kinyarwanda, the local language, Dukunde Kawa means "love coffee".In the Northern Province of Rwanda, with small plots of land and manyhigh peaks, coffee trees are often grown with other food crops in thefamily gardens, making its unique taste but high quality.</p><p>After some experimentation, I found that this lot shines best withJames Hoffmann’s brewing method (<ahref="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1oB1oDrDkHM">video here</a>),which precisely highlights the characteristics of the Red Bourbonvariety. The aroma is appealing, with sweet notes of raspberry jam and ahint of chocolate. On the palate, it delivers a burst of blood orange, apronounced citric acidity, and a silky mouthfeel, though slightly thin.I adjusted the brewing parameters but noticed no significantimprovement. Overall, it’s a unique and memorable specialty coffee.(<strong>My</strong> 43/50)</p><h4 id="mok-coffee-ethiopia-tibebu-roba-natural">MOK Coffee, Ethiopia,Tibebu Roba, Natural</h4><blockquote><p>Profile</p><ul><li>Roaster: MOK Coffee, Brussels, Belgium<br /></li><li>Region: Yirgacheffe<br /></li><li>Producer: Tibebu Roba<br /></li><li>Variety: Kurume &amp; Wolisho<br /></li><li>Process: Natural</li></ul></blockquote><p><a href="https://mokcoffee.be/">MOK Coffee</a> was a fantastic microcoffee roastery, founded in 2012 by two times Belgian Cup TastersChampion Jens Crabbé. They focus on roasting in small batches of 10-23kg, allowing precise control over the process to ensure the tastingprofile of the bean is just right. Though their selection is limited,they offer rare, high-quality options that are definitely worth keepingan eye on.</p><p>Yirgacheffe, Ethiopia is undoubtedly a renowned origin forhigh-quality coffee. The plantations here are typically managed in adistinctive way, with most growing in a natural, semi-wild environment.The shade provided by the wild trees in combination with the veryfertile soil provide the perfect ecosystem to offer a a beautifullybalanced cup of coffee. On the other hand, Tibebu Roba, a charismaticcoffee farmer, is an inspiration for smallholders, and his commitment toquality has earned an admiration within the coffee community.</p><p>This coffee is so memorable that combines aromas of apple and somefloral hints. Up-front yoghurt dominates, swiftly followed juicy orangeand lime. The body is light, showcasing the clean, bright, andhigh-acidity profile. When it's cooling down, it resembles iced tea witha soft limey finish. This Yirga-coffee is consistently stunning whateverthe brewing methods. It definitely fulfils my vision of a specialitycoffee and I will keep an eye on Yirgacheffe anyway.(<strong>My</strong> 45/50)</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Lifestyle</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Coffee</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Fantastic Night, A Satisfactory Score</title>
    <link href="/A-Fantastic-Night-A-Satisfactory-Score/"/>
    <url>/A-Fantastic-Night-A-Satisfactory-Score/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>The 'positive result' match tonight Aston Villa hostJuventus in the Champions League.</em></strong></p><span id="more"></span><p>In the fourth round of the UEFA Champions League group stage,Juventus traveled to Birmingham, England, to face Aston Villa. As adevoted Juventus fan, there was no way I could miss the opportunity towitness this match in person and cheer on the team led by their newcoach, Thiago Motta.</p><p>This was my third time watching Juventus live, but my first-everChampions League match. It was also my second time attending a footballmatch in England - the last time being in Manchester, where I watchedMan City host Copenhagen. Embarrassingly, despite having lived in Londonfor over three years, I have yet to attend a single Premier Leaguematch. I got my ticket for this game from <ahref="https://www.livefootballtickets.com/">Live Football Tickets</a> asa resale one, which came at a hefty price. The football culture here inthe UK is truly enviable.</p><p>Villa Park Arena is located not far from the city centre, nestled ina setting that feels more like the countryside. With a history spanningover 120 years, this iconic stadium has borne witness to Aston VillaFootball Club's glorious moments and holds a sacred place in the heartsof its fans. Notably, I was fortunate to spot the Juventus team busbefore entering the stadium. Its striking zebra-striped design wasespecially impressive.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post6/outside-1.jpg" title="Villa Park Arena" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post6/outside-2.jpg" title="Juventus Bus" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"></div></div><p>Currently, Juventus is grappling with a severe injury crisis, with asmany as 10 players sidelined, including Bremer, Douglas Luiz, Nico, andVlahovic. This left today’s bench with only 6 players, two of whom weregoalkeepers and two youth players. My seat in the lower tier provided aclose-up view of the warm-up, where Cambiaso, Locatelli, and Yildizstood out as key pillars of the team.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post6/warmup-1.jpg" title="Gatti" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post6/warmup-2.jpg" title="Cambiaso" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post6/warmup-3.jpg" title="Kalulu" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post6/warmup-4.jpg" title="Locatelli" /></div></div></div><p>The match kicked off with an impressive opening - sparks andfireworks lit up the scene. As the iconic Champions League anthemplayed, the game officially began. The atmosphere at the stadium waselectric. The home fans were fully engaged, passionately supportingtheir team. Despite being outnumbered, Juventus fans did their best tomake their presence felt, cheering loudly to encourage the awayside.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post6/beginning-1.jpg" title="Fireworks" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post6/beginning-2.jpg" title="Sparks" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"></div></div><p>The match itself was somewhat uneventful. Given the packed scheduleand severe injury crisis, the away team displayed remarkable resilience,aiming at least for a draw, which is more or less moving. If not forMartinez's incredible save and the disallowed goal due to a foul on DiGregorio in the final moments, the game’s balance might have shifted. Atthe final whistle, it ended in a 0-0 draw, with Juventus successfullysecuring a precious point.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post6/game-1.jpg" title="starting line-up" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post6/game-2.jpg"title="Player of match: Conceicao" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post6/game-3.jpg" title="Yildiz" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post6/game-4.jpg" title="Cambiaso" /></div></div></div><p align="right"><font color=grey size=2>Copyright: Juventus.com</font></p><p>With this result, the Champions League group stage is now halfwaythrough. Juventus sits at 7 points, where advancing directly to the top8 seems unlikely, but they’re also not at risk of being eliminatedoutright. It’s highly probable they’ll find themselves in the playoffround. Looking ahead, the team will need to manage the remaining matchescarefully, hope for a quick recovery for the injured players, and focuson staying competitive in Serie A. Securing a ticket to next season’sChampions League remains the top priority. Forza Juve!</p><p>Although the "expedition" was costly, and I had to be cautioussurrounded by the home fans, none of this mattered because:</p><p><strong>Juve, storia di un grande amore.</strong></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Lifestyle</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Football</tag>
      
      <tag>Juventus</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Press: Latest Work Featured on Front Cover of J. Mater. Chem. B</title>
    <link href="/Press-Latest-Work-Featured-on-Front-Cover-of-J.-Mater.-Chem.-B/"/>
    <url>/Press-Latest-Work-Featured-on-Front-Cover-of-J.-Mater.-Chem.-B/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>Excited to see our latest electrochemical-SERS work nowfeatured on the front cover of J. Mater. Chem. B.</em></strong></p><span id="more"></span><p><font color=#CC3333><strong>Many configurations to Dr. Jones and ourPI Dr. Lee, fabulous work has been done!</strong></font></p><p>I am proud of being involved in this electrochemical-SERS project,dominated by Dr. Jones, since my master study. I made very littlecontribution but learnt a lot from Tabby, be it SERS andelectrochemistry fundamentals, experimental methodology, and dataprocessing with Python. It is definitely a kick-start for my current PhDproject.</p><p>Specifically to this paper, it combines electrochemical SERS (E-SERS)and machine learning for the quantitative multiplexed detection of uricacid and creatinine, which has advantages in terms of facile procedure,low limits of detection, and high prediction accuracy.</p><p><img src="/img/post4/front_cover.png"title="Front cover, 07 November 2024, Volume 12, Issue 41, Journal of Materials Chemistry B" /></p><p>Once again, congrats to our lab on this decent work!</p><p></br></p><p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tb01552e"><font size=2>TabithaJones, Deyue Zhou, Jia Liu, Ivan P. Parkin, and Tung-Chun Lee,“Quantitative multiplexing of uric acid and creatinine usingpolydisperse plasmonic nanoparticles enabled by electrochemical SERS andmachine learning”, <strong><em>J. Mater. Chem. B</em></strong>, 2024,<strong>12</strong>, 10563-10572.</font></a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Lab</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Spectroscopy</tag>
      
      <tag>Journal</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>An Automatic Baseline Correction Method for Raman Spectra</title>
    <link href="/An-Automatic-Baseline-Correction-Method-for-Raman-Spectra/"/>
    <url>/An-Automatic-Baseline-Correction-Method-for-Raman-Spectra/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>With a few lines of code, we can easily batch subtractspectral background.</em></strong></p><span id="more"></span><div class="note note-info">            <p>In this post:</p><ul><li>An algorithm based on asymmetric least squares (ALS) smoothing<br /></li><li>Python code implementation</li></ul>          </div><p><font size=2><strong>Credit: Dr Tabitha Jones, my colleague whosupervised me a lot not just this portion, currently is ResearchAssociate at University of Cambridge.</strong></font></p><h3 id="fluorescence-in-raman-spectroscopy">Fluorescence in RamanSpectroscopy</h3><p>The signal in Raman spectroscopy has three components: vibrationalbands, noise, and fluorescence. Fluorescence occurs when a photon of theincoming radiation is absorbed by an orbital electron in a molecule ofthe material, exciting it to a higher energy level. The practicalconsequence of this in Raman spectroscopy is that intense fluorescenceemissions from a sample can obscure weaker vibrational fingerprints andreduce the quality of spectra. Thus, it is necessary to remove thebaseline drift in spectroscopic analysis.</p><p>Background subtraction is a crucial step in the preprocessing ofRaman spectra, it can be implemented by either manual or automationmeans in professional plotting software (e.g. Origin). However, theseapproaches are usually subjective, time-consuming and of limitedreproducibility, and a highly compelling alternative is algorithm-basedautomated signal processing.</p><h3 id="als-baseline-correction">ALS Baseline Correction</h3><p>Asymmetric Least Squares (ALS) is a growing baseline estimationmethod, developed by Eiler<a href="#fn1" class="footnote-ref"id="fnref1" role="doc-noteref"><sup>1</sup></a>, that uses an asymmetricweighting of deviations to smooth data and estimate a baseline,extending ideas presented by Whittaker 80 years ago. This smoother issimple and fast, allowing to be programmed in a few lines of code.</p><p>Specially, it refers to the algorithm based on searching a smoothline (<span class="math inline">\(z\)</span>) lower than theexperimental data (<span class="math inline">\(y\)</span>) by penalizingthe second derivative of the former. Mathematically, it is brieflyexpressed as the following functional:<br /><span class="math display">\[F=\sum_{i}w_i(y_i-z_i)^2+\lambda\sum_{i}(z_i&#39;&#39;)^2\notag\]</span></p><p>where the summation runs over all points of the <em>x</em>-axis,<span class="math inline">\(w_i\)</span> is chosen asymmetrically: <spanclass="math inline">\(w_i = p\)</span> if <spanclass="math inline">\(y_i &gt; z_i\)</span> and <spanclass="math inline">\(w_i=1-p\)</span> otherwise, and <spanclass="math inline">\(\lambda\)</span> is the penalty parameter for thesecond derivative. In a nutshell, this method can: Quickly correct andascertain a baseline and Retain signal peak information.</p><h3 id="implementation-application">Implementation &amp;Application</h3><p>Based on the algorithm, Python <code>Scipy</code> package is calledto defined the corresponding function, which then can be used for rawspectral data ergodic extraction and batch processing.</p><figure class="highlight python"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br><span class="line">15</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs Python"><span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> numpy <span class="hljs-keyword">as</span> np<br><span class="hljs-keyword">from</span> scipy.sparse <span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> csc_matrix<br><span class="hljs-keyword">from</span> scipy.sparse <span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> spdiags<br><span class="hljs-keyword">from</span> scipy.sparse.linalg <span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> spsolve<br><br><span class="hljs-keyword">def</span> <span class="hljs-title function_">ALSBaselineCorrection</span>(<span class="hljs-params">y, lam=<span class="hljs-number">1E6</span>, p=<span class="hljs-number">0.001</span>, niter=<span class="hljs-number">30</span></span>):<br>    m = <span class="hljs-built_in">len</span>(y)<br>    w = np.ones(m)<br>    D = csc_matrix(np.diff(np.eye(m), <span class="hljs-number">3</span>))<br>    <span class="hljs-keyword">for</span> i <span class="hljs-keyword">in</span> <span class="hljs-built_in">range</span>(niter):<br>        W = spdiags(w, <span class="hljs-number">0</span>, m, m)<br>        Z = W + lam * D.dot(D.transpose())<br>        z = spsolve(Z, w * y)<br>        w = p * (y &gt; z) + (<span class="hljs-number">1</span> - p) * (y &lt; z)<br>    <span class="hljs-keyword">return</span> z<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Here is an example of my own experimental data. In Surface EnhancedRaman Scattering (SERS) sensing of adenine, a purine nucleotide base,high fluorescence exhibits due to the presence of graphene oxide in themeasurement system. As can be seen, after ALS smoothing, the driftingbaseline is pulled back to zero intensity, and almost all the Ramansignals are well preserved.</p><p><img src="/img/post3/spectra.png"title="Surface Enhanced Raman Spectrum of Adenine Before/After Baseline Correction" /></p><p>Furthermore, this method allows us to quickly process large volumesof spectra without handling them one by one, making it efficient androbust.</p><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"role="doc-endnotes"><hr /><ol><li id="fn1"><p><ahref="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/ac034173t">Paul H. C. Eilers, "APerfect Smoother", <em>Anal. Chem.</em> 2003, 75, 14, 3631–3636.</a><ahref="#fnref1" class="footnote-back" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p></li></ol></section>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Lab</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Python</tag>
      
      <tag>Spectroscopy</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Best Speciality Coffee Shops in London</title>
    <link href="/Best-Speciality-Coffee-Shops-in-London/"/>
    <url>/Best-Speciality-Coffee-Shops-in-London/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>London is leading in volume of speciality coffee shops,yet their qualities...?</em></strong> <span id="more"></span></p><div class="note note-danger">            <p>Last updated 2024-10-21</p>          </div><div class="note note-info">            <p>At a glance:</p><ul><li>Special Guests Coffee, Marylebone<br /></li><li>Monmunth Coffee Company, Covent Garden<br /></li><li>Kiss the Hippo Coffee, Fitzrovia<br /></li><li>Omotesando Koffee, Fitzrovia<br /></li><li>Prufrock Coffee, Farringdon</li><li>WatchHouse, Spitalfields<br /></li><li>Nagare Cafe, Spitalfields</li></ul>          </div><p>Coffee is a necessity in my life. It's no wonder that discovering newcoffee shops while traveling has become one of my favourite pastimes.Despite being fascinated by Nordic genre, I've come up with a list of myfavourite independent speciality coffee shops in London over the lastthree years of living here. You simply shouldn’t miss them out if you'reinto speciality coffee and come to London.</p><h3 id="special-guests-coffee"><ahref="https://specialguestscoffee.com/"><strong>Special GuestsCoffee</strong></a></h3><p>Special Guests is the youngest independent brand in my list. Foundedin 2022, it is an emerging force within the London coffee scene directedby a two-time UK Barista Championship winner, Paul Ross. Located a fewsteps away from the commercial area though, their first store attractsthe most loyal fans - I became one of them after my first tasting.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/special_guests_1.jpg"title="Special Guests: shop" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/special_guests_2.jpg"title="Special Guests: atmosphere" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"></div></div><p>In Special Guests, you will be presented with one of the mostextensive specialty filter coffee menus showcasing some of the rarest,highest quality coffees from the world’s leading roasters. On my firstvisit, Paul advised and brewed me a pour-over, featured "UN017" - YunlanEstate, Gesha. This unique washed Gesha from Yunnan, China, results in acup of coffee with a clean and juicy flavour profile, that I could feelnotes of pear, white tea and floral.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/special_guests_3.jpg"title="Special Guests: filter coffee" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/special_guests_4.jpg"title="Special Guests: Paul &amp; me" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"></div></div><p>If you are a genuine artisan coffee lover expecting a quiet and pureatmosphere for a cup, you don't want to miss it.</p><h3 id="monmouth-coffee-company"><ahref="https://www.monmouthcoffee.co.uk/"><strong>Monmouth CoffeeCompany</strong></a></h3><p>When talking about specialty coffee in London, Monmouth is amust-mention. It’s an undisputed pioneer and one of the first to focuson the origin of the beans. I used to be a devoted subscriber (now Irarely brew coffee at home), always able to taste specialty coffee fromaround the world at a reasonable price.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/monmonth_1.jpg" title="Monmonth: front" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/monmonth_2.jpg" title="Monmonth: bar" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/monmonth_3.jpg" title="Monmonth: bakery" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/monmonth_4.jpg"title="Monmonth: iced filter coffee" /></div></div></div><p>The first store, located in Covent Garden, has nearly 50 years ofhistory. I don’t know much about its past, but nowadays, it’s so popularthat I’ve never managed to snag a seat there. I usually opted for thefilter coffee of the day, though I seldom got much information about it- the baristas are just too busy. Nevertheless, it came out consistentlygood and had never let me down.</p><p>If you're focused on the beans themselves and want to take some home,this is the place to be. But if you're looking to while away some time,the stream of visitors standing with their cups might make you thinktwice.</p><h3 id="kiss-the-hippo-coffee"><a href="https://kissthehippo.com/">Kissthe Hippo Coffee</a></h3><p>If I had to keep just one coffee shop on the list, I'd pick Kiss theHippo without hesitation. It’s just a few seconds away from my college,and was the first artisan coffee shop I discovered in London. Kiss theHippo is, first and foremost, a high-quality coffee roaster and openedits first store in Richmond in 2018, and I’m delighted to see it hasbeen expanding to Fitzrovia and other key locations across London.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/kiss_the_hippo_1.jpg"title="Kiss the Hippo: front" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/kiss_the_hippo_2.jpg"title="Kiss the Hippo: beans &amp; gear" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/kiss_the_hippo_3.jpg"title="Kiss the Hippo: menu" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/kiss_the_hippo_4.jpg"title="Kiss the Hippo: flat white &amp; Japanese iced coffee" /></div></div></div><p>At Kiss the Hippo Coffee, Fitzrovia, I was always provided withfriendly hospitality, and more importantly, exceptionally crafted andflavoured cups. In addition to the best-ever flat white, I love theirJapanese iced coffee, a combination of pour-over and ice-blending -simply fantastic. I won’t spoil too much, but if you’re visiting OxfordStreet, it is a must-stop.</p><h3 id="omotesando-koffee"><ahref="http://ooo-koffee.com/london.html">Omotesando Koffee</a></h3><p>Omotesando Koffee, hailing from Tokyo's Omotesando district, bringsmodern Japanese coffee culture to Fitzrovia. Following the Japanese<em>shokunin</em> principle, a lifelong dedication to one's craft, ithas since gone truly global with outposts in Tokyo, Hong Kong, Singaporeand of course London.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/omotesando_1.jpg"title="Omotesando: front" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/omotesando_2.jpg"title="Omotesando: meau" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/omotesando_3.jpg"title="Omotesando: iced Omotesando koffee" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"></div></div><p>It never misses a spot on any list, which is why it has garnered adevoted following. If you're willing to spend some time in line, itdefinitely will never disappoint. I usually go for their signatureOmotesando iced coffee, and always have to take it away.</p><h3 id="prufrock-coffee"><a href="https://prufrockcoffee.com/">PrufrockCoffee</a></h3><p>If you’re into the specialty coffee scene and you live in London,you’ve definitely heard of Prufrock Coffee. It was founded by threecoffee enthusiasts in 2009, then was acquired by social media baristaJames Hoffmann in 2017. It continues to be a sought-after destinationfor visitors from around the world, with its commitment to coffeeeducation being what sets it apart.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/prufrock_1.jpg" title="Prufrock: front" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/prufrock_2.jpg"title="Prufrock: beans &amp; derivatives" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/prufrock_3.jpg" title="Prufrock: seats" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/prufrock_4.jpg"title="Prufrock: flat white &amp; iced filter coffee" /></div></div></div><p>Prufrock Coffee is one of those neighbourhood gems which make me alittle sad about not living in Farringdon thus not having it on mydoorstep. Nonetheless, I've made the visit twice and both times I'vebeen impressed. This place has everything about crafted coffee - anextensive selection of beans, professional and friendly baristas, and adecent atmosphere. I almost wish I could order five cups at once - theyall offer an exceptional and unique experience.</p><h3 id="watchhouse"><a href="https://watchhouse.com">WatchHouse</a></h3><p>I usually have a bias against coffee chains as most of the time, byyielding to supply chain costs and product consistency, the quality ofthe coffee may go down, which is unacceptable for dedicated baristas andcoffee enthusiasts. WatchHouse might be an exception. Starting in SouthLondon, it now has twenty locations, all are designed to play acontemporary role in the modern coffee experience, while also preservingtheir unique history in the community.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/watchhouse_1.jpg"title="WatchHouse: front" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/watchhouse_2.jpg"title="WatchHouse: menu" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/watchhouse_3.jpg" title="WatchHouse: bar" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/watchhouse_4.jpg"title="WatchHouse: flat white" /></div></div></div><p>Regrettably, I haven’t visited all of their stores, but the one inSpitalfields Market left a deep impression on me. It has fully retainedits identity as an independent coffee shop, with modernist designperfectly blending with the original elements of its industrial heritage- not to mention the meticulously brewed cups. It has reasonable pricesamong all specialty coffee shops, but the quality is not compromised,whether for batch brew or flat white, far outpacing most of thewell-known chain brands. If you’re looking for a decent cup of coffeeand happen to be near a WatchHouse, don’t hesitate to step inside.</p><h3 id="nagare-cafe"><a href="https://nagare.co.uk">Nagare Cafe</a></h3><p>Nagare means flowing like a river in Japanese. It’s another coffeeshop in London with a Japanese aesthetic, blending seamlessly with thelocal historical charm. It calls a Grade II-listed Georgian buildingthat sports one of Spitalfields most recognizable historic shop frontshome. The cosily minimalist interior is the perfect foil to carefullybrewed espresso and filter.</p><div class="group-image-container"><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/nagare_1.jpg" title="Nagare: front" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/nagare_2.jpg" title="Nagare: bar" /></div></div><div class="group-image-row"><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/nagare_3.jpg"title="Nagare: beans &amp; gear" /></div><div class="group-image-wrap"><img src="/img/post2/nagare_4.jpg"title="Nagare: reserved filter coffee" /></div></div></div><p>The main focus here is on pour-over coffee, with a dedicated filtermenu offering beans from some of the world’s top roasters, such as Aprilfrom Copenhagen, Nylon from Singapore, AOMA from Osaka, Stopover fromTaiwan, and Market Lane from Australia. If you’re into hand-made coffee,Nagare Cafe is definitely worth a special trip, even if, like me, youlive in West London.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Lifestyle</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Coffee</tag>
      
      <tag>London</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Build Personal Website with Hexo and GitHub Pages on Mac</title>
    <link href="/Build-Personal-Websiite-with-Hexo-and-GitHub-Pages-on-Mac/"/>
    <url>/Build-Personal-Websiite-with-Hexo-and-GitHub-Pages-on-Mac/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>Knock on new home's door.</em></strong></p><span id="more"></span><div class="note note-info">            <p>In this post:</p><ul><li><p>How-tos for building a personal blog</p></li><li><p>Useful links for reference</p></li></ul>          </div><h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3><p>It has been long time since I would like to own a particular space torecord my life, and until now I've finally started creating my personalwebsite here. Among a variety of schemes, I opt to <strong>Hexo + GitHubPages</strong>, which is friendly to noob like me.</p><p><a href="https://hexo.io"><strong>Hexo</strong></a> is a fast, simple&amp; powerful blog framework. Simply write post in Markdown and Hexogenerates static files deployed to GitHub Pages.</p><p>As the first post, I am writing this article just in case anyone whois also interested in having a personal website but hasn't been preparedyet. On the other hand, it will be an importent reference for myself tore-create the environment efficiently when I change the Mac or migratedata in the future.</p><h3 id="environment-setup">Environment setup</h3><p>Install Homebrew</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">/bin/bash -c <span class="hljs-string">&quot;<span class="hljs-subst">$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubsuercontent.com/Homebrew/install/HEAD/install.sh)</span>&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Install Node.js</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">brew install node<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Install Git</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">brew install git<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Install Hexo</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">npm install -g hexo-cli<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h3 id="initialize-hexo">Initialize Hexo</h3><p>Once Hexo is installed, create a new folder for Hexo, and keep inmind the <code>&lt;path&gt;</code>.</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash"><span class="hljs-built_in">cd</span> &lt;path&gt;<span class="hljs-comment"># enter target folder</span><br>hexo init <span class="hljs-comment"># initialize Hexo</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>We can see essential folders/files are generatred. And<code>_config.yml</code> is the "site config" file in Hexo root dict,personalize the top contents when required.</p><p>Here are some basic commands to compile Hexo below.</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">hexo clean<span class="hljs-comment"># clear the static files and cache</span><br>hexo g<span class="hljs-comment"># generate static web files locally</span><br>hexo s<span class="hljs-comment"># start a local sever for preview</span><br>hexo d<span class="hljs-comment"># deploy after generation finish</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h3 id="deploy-github-pages">Deploy GitHub Pages</h3><p>Create a repo in GitHub named as username.github.io.</p><p>Add SHH key to GitHub account.</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">git config --glabal user.name <span class="hljs-string">&quot;username&quot;</span><br>git config --global user.email <span class="hljs-string">&quot;example@example.com&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Then generate SHH key.</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">ssh-keygen -t rsa -C <span class="hljs-string">&quot;example@example.com&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Find <code>id_ras.pub</code> file under dict<code>/User/.ssh/id_rsa.pub</code>.</p><p>Open <code>id_ras.pub</code> with TextEdit, and copy/paste to Githubaccount setting.</p><p>Check if successful.</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">ssh -T git@github.com<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Install deployer plugin.</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">npm install hexo-deployer-git --save<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Open <code>_config.yml</code> with TextEdit and scroll down to thebottom, modify as below.</p><figure class="highlight yaml"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs yaml"><span class="hljs-comment"># Deployment</span><br><span class="hljs-comment">## Docs: https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment</span><br><span class="hljs-attr">deploy:</span><br>  <span class="hljs-attr">type:</span> <span class="hljs-string">git</span><br>  <span class="hljs-attr">repo:</span> <span class="hljs-string">https://github.com/username/username.github.io.git</span><br>  <span class="hljs-attr">branch:</span> <span class="hljs-string">master</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Deploy to GitHub Pages.</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">hexo clean<br>hexo g --d<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><div class="note note-success">            <p>Now we can login our personal website using username.github.io <spanclass="github-emoji" data-alias="tada" style=""data-fallback-src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f389.png?v8">🎉</span></p>          </div><h3 id="personalize-domain">Personalize domain</h3><p>It should be much cooler if we could have a custom domain. On top ofGitHub Pages, my scheme is <strong>GoDaddy + Cloudflare</strong> -cheap, save and accessible.</p><p>Here are the brief steps:</p><p>Step 1: Buy a domain from <ahref="https://www.godaddy.com/en-uk"><strong>GoDaddy</strong></a></p><p>Step 2: DNS management by <ahref="https://www.cloudflare.com/"><strong>Cloudflare</strong></a></p><ul><li>Change to Cloudflare-branded nameservers<br /></li><li>Add DNS records with IP addresses for GitHub Pages</li></ul><p>Step 3: GitHub custom domain</p><p>Step 4: HTTPS &amp; SSL encryption</p><ul><li>Page Rules set as "Always Use HTTPS"<br /></li><li>SSL/TLS encryption set as "Full"<br /></li><li>Tick "Always Use HTTPS" under Edge Certificates</li></ul><div class="note note-success">            <p>Now we can login our personal website using custom domain <spanclass="github-emoji" data-alias="tada" style=""data-fallback-src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f389.png?v8">🎉</span></p>          </div><h3 id="customize-hexo-theme">Customize Hexo theme</h3><p>Select a <a href="https://hexo.io/themes/"><strong>Hexotheme</strong></a>, and make our blog more pretty.</p><p>I prefer <ahref="https://hexo.io/themes/"><strong>Fluid</strong></a>, an elegantMaterial-Design theme, particularly for writing posts. If you favour theother theme, the configuration method should be similar.</p><p>Download Fluid.</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">npm install --save hexo-theme-fluid<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Then <code>_config.fluid.yml</code> in root dict is created forcustom.</p><p>Modify <code>_config.yml</code> in root dict as follows to starttheme.</p><figure class="highlight yaml"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs yaml"><span class="hljs-comment"># Extensions</span><br><span class="hljs-comment">## Plugins: https://hexo.io/plugins/</span><br><span class="hljs-comment">## Themes: https://hexo.io/themes/</span><br><span class="hljs-attr">theme:</span> <span class="hljs-string">fluid</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Creating the About Page.</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">hexo new page about<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>For more configuration, please refer to <ahref="https://hexo.fluid-dev.com/docs/en/start/"><strong>Hexo FluidDocs</strong></a>.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Computer</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Hexo</tag>
      
      <tag>Markdown</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
